Keiron Goodwin

Sheffield, S13. Mobile: +44 07471 947226. keirong@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/keiron-lee-goodwin-aab541a

Personal Profile

I'm an experienced software engineer with over 20 years experience having worked for Plusnet and Sanderson working across the LAMP stack, C#, .NET, Linux and Windows environments in front end and back-end code.

Since being made redundant in 2020, I've taken some time to explore my interest in videography and acting. Web Development has always been a passion of mine, I therefore recently completed a software developer bootcamp with The Developer Academy using the MERN stack and am eager to use my skills and experience in this exciting field. Also recently won a mini online hackathon organised by the local BCS using skills learnt during the Developer Academy course.

Skills

- Advanced Visual Basic 6/VB.Net
- Advanced Pick Data basic/Unidata
- Advanced HTML 5
- Advanced CSS
- Proficient Core JavaScript knowledge
- Proficient PHP5 experience
- Proficient MySQL
- Proficient React/NodeJS
- Proficient SQL Server
- Proficient Bootstrap 5
- Novice .Net Framework 4
- Novice WPF
- Novice MVC
- Novice Silverlight
- Novice jQuery
- Problem Solving
- Customer support
- Time management
- Team Leading

Work Experience

Sanderson, Software Developer, July 2003 - October 2020

Developed forms within VB6 in various areas of ERP system, those being Purchasing, Sales, HR, Wages, Financial, Stock control. Shortly before leaving I stayed on for a few months in the role of customer support specialist.

- Created an add on for Microsoft Outlook in VB.Net to process incoming emails from customers and automate ordering amongst other things.
- Worked on forms for a new version of the ERP software in C# and Typescript, also using HTML5, CSS, WPF, MVC, Silverlight, .NET Framework 4 amongst other technology.
- Dealt with customers when support was required for bugs and modifications.

PlusNet, Software Developer, January 2001 – September 2002

Worked within a LAMP stack developing the financial back-end code for customer billing via BACS etc. Worked on front end web pages on the main PlusNet website adding amongst other things site usage tracking software. Also gained experience acting as team leader when the main team leader was absent.

TBS, Software Developer, January 2000 - January 2001

I rewrote the data processing end of Taskmaster software using VB6 to include use of custom DLLs written for or by customers. Also wrote cursors for use in SQL Server

Education & Qualifications

2005 – 2011 Sheffield University HNC Archaeology (Part of Human and Natural Environments degree) 1997 – 1999 Sheffield Hallam University HND Computer Science

Projects

Local Tourism Website: Deployed: Local Tourism Site GitHub: Code for Local Tourism Site

Project done for bootcamp at the Developer Academy, the site shows examples of photography I've done in three local tourist areas in and around Sheffield with a bit of information about each area and a map to show viewers of the site where to go. Each photograph has a little information about it as well. Needs polishing up a bit but quite happy about the layout and appearance of the site.

Adventure Game Deployed: Adventure Game site GitHub: Code for Adventure Game site

This project again was done for part of the ongoing bootcamp course with the Developer Academy, we were asked to create a text adventure game using JavaScript, I however decided to take this one step further and create a graphical adventure game with text descriptions as well (just to cover myself), I decided to try and come up with a modern day version of a game I used to play in the mid 80's on a Mattel Aquarius, it still needs to be finished but it's playable in a very limited form at the minute. If you would like a play the W, A, S, D keys control movement in north, south, east, west style directions, Q and E turn left and right respectively, R is used to loot defeated enemies, SPACE BAR attacks creatures you come across and H uses a health potion if you have one in your inventory.

Quiz Project site Deployed: Quiz Project site GitHub: Code for Quiz Project site

This project is another one done as part of the bootcamp course at the Developer Academy, we were asked to create a quiz with multiple pages and options per question with a page that showed the results, it was meant to run as one page despite having multiple question pages. I decided to have a go at creating a quiz similar the the ones you find on social media sites that ask multiple questions and result in showing you which character you might be out of a film/tv/comic series. I decided to go with the X-Men. Quite happy with how it turned out although as with all the projects I do think that I should go back and polish them up a bit as I learn more.

Caesar Cypher site Deployed: Caesar Cypher site Code: Code for Caesar Cypher site

Final project for now is another for the bootcamp course at the Developer Academy, the remit for this one was to create a site that involved using the Caesar Cypher to encode plain text and allow you to decrypt it afterwards, I extended this by allowing the user to use multiple key codes to encrypt the text. Quite happy with both the layout and how this turned out, code wise it was rather easy to complete but I think the simple design looks good too.